TECH / SKILLS

HTML **UX/UI DESIGN** CSS WIRE-FRAMING **BOOTSTRAP** PROTOTYPING **TAIILWINDS USER RESEARCH JAVASCRIPT** MOCK UPS **JQUERY GRAPHIC DESIGN** REACT PHOTOGRAPHY **EXPRESS IMAGE EDITING** NODE.JS GIT/GITHUB WORDPRESS SMARTLOOK

SOFTWARE

VS CODE PHOTOSHOP BOOTSTRAP STUDIO LIGHTROOM ADOBE XD **ILLUSTRATOR**

SOFT SKILLS

CRITICAL THINKING AUTHENTICITY COMMUNICATION TIME MANAGEMENT **FAST LEARNER** RELIABILITY **DETAIL ORIENTATED** INDEPENDANT

PERSONAL

Birthday : 11 April 1994 South African & Greek **Passports**

: English Languages

CONTACT

Claremont, Cape Town

+27 84 413 5465

nikitabatlis@live.com

www.nikitabatlis.github.io/portfolio/

linkedin.com/in/nikitabatlis/

github.com/NikitaBatlis

NIKITA BATLIS

Web Developer | UX/UI Designer

PROFILE

I thrive on creative front-end challenges and enjoy implementing UI trends into my current projects. I have a particular interest in accessible UX design and believe the key to a product's long-term success is putting the user's experience first.

JOB HISTORY

UX/UI Developer

Nov 2020 - Present

Handy Cats | www.handycats.com | Cape Town

Initially a design-focused position, that quickly branched into the frontend development of our new flagship project's marketing pages. I also set up and starting monitoring the analytics of the live sites - I saw a lot of opportunities to optimise the frontend of the projects to improve usability, while ultimately improving the time to conversion.

Responsibilities: user research & testing, analytics, wireframing, prototyping, graphic design,

Component development & styling for marketing pages.

HTML, CSS, Tailwinds, JavaScript, Wordpress, Elementor, Vue(just started), Tools userd:

Adobe XD, Illustrator, Smartlook

Photographer & Worpress Designer

Apr 2019 - Oct 2020

Freelance Student | Cape Town

Commissioned portraiture, location and real estate photography. Visual branding and mock ups. As well as Wordpress website theme setup and graphic designs for small local start-ups.

Location Scout & Researcher

Nov 2018 - Mar 2019

Cape Town Productions | www.ctprod.co.za | Cape Town

A summer contract managing and updating the company's location database while researching and scouting new locations around Cape Town. Along with assisting on set and in-office coordinators.

Dec 2017 - Sep 2018 Stewardess

Katara | 123m Private Motor Yacht | Spain

Working & living closely with a team of 70 multinationals. Managing & maintaining luxury yacht interiors while delivering 10 Star service for Arab Royalty.

EDUCATION

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT BOOTCAMP

HYPERIONDEV, CAPE TOWN

A full MERN stack web development course that taught me to build dynamic, data-driven web applications with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, MongoDB, Express & React.

2020

BRAND & MARKETING MANAGEMENT

VEGA SCHOOL, CAPE TOWN

Part time 6 month course to develop both theoretical and practical knowledge in the field of brand building and digital marketing.

2019

PROFESSIONAL DIPLOMA IN UX DESIGN

UX DESIGN INSTITUTE, IRELAND

Correspondence 1 year diploma in professional UX design user theory, research methods, prototyping and wireframing work-flows, as well as design thinking and analysis.

2019 - 2020

CERTIFICATE IN COMMERCIAL **PHOTOGRAPHY**

VEGA SCHOOL, CAPE TOWN

Full time 2 year certification in professional photography, image editing and manipulation, as well as graphic design.

2013 - 2014

REFERENCES UPON REOUEST